Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.inventory3 Mss.B.B61.inventory03
American Philosophical Society
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents C
  - Cole, F.C. [Fay Cooper] (Box 16)
    - From Boas, 1938 May 9; 1p
    - From Boas, 1940 Feb. 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1940 Mar. 28; 1p
    - From Boas, 1941 Jan. 10; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 Mar. 16; 1p
  - Cole, Fay Cooper (Box 16)
    - To Boas, 1912 Feb. 13; 2p
    - To Boas, 1912 May 6
    - To Boas, 1912 July 22
    - To Boas, 1912 Aug. 12; 2p
    - To Boas, 1912 Aug. 21
    - To Boas, 1912 Sep. 14
    - To Boas, 1913 Sep. 23
    - To Boas, 1914 Sep. 28; 2p
    - To Boas, 1914 Oct. 20
    - To Boas, 1914 Oct. 26
    - To Boas, 1914 Nov. 7
    - To Boas, 1924 Jan. 23; 3p
    - To Boas, 1926 Feb. 6; 2p
    - To Boas, 1926 Feb. 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1926 June 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1927 May 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1927 Nov. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 Feb. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 19; 1p
      - (see Danforth, C.H.), 1929 Dec. 31
    - To Boas, 1930 Feb. 4; 1p
    - co-signer: Wilson, E.B., 1930 Feb. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 June 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec. 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Jan. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Nov. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Jan. 20; 1p
  - Cole, Frank N. (Box 16)
    - From Boas, [1913?] 1920 Aug. 10; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 13; 1p
  - Cole, Louis [Lois?] / Dwight (Box 16)
    - From Boas, 1936 Apr. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Mar. 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Apr. 1; 1p
  - Cole, M.C. (Box 16)
    - From Boas, 1935 Nov. 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Oct. 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Nov. 19; 1p
  - Coleman, Gerald R. (Box 16)
    - From Boas, 1936 Dec. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Dec. 8; 1p
  - Coleman, L.V. (Box 16)
    - From Boas, 1929 July 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 July 6; 1p
  - Coleman, N.R. (Box 16)
    - To Boas, 1925 May 19; 1p
  - Coleman, Paul L. (Box 16)
    - To Boas, 1942 Apr. 30; 1p
  - College of Physicians and Surgeons (Box 16)
    - From Med. Cen. Anti-War Committee, 1935 May 25
  - College Teachers Union, Columbia (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1940 Apr. 29; 2p
  - Collett (Box 17)
    - To U.S. Dept. Ind. Affairs, 1933 Sep. 18; 1p
    - attached to letter from Gordon, P.W. to FB, 1933 Sep. 30
  - Collie, G.L. (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1919 Nov. 13; 1p
      - see FB to Tyler, J.M., 1919 Nov. 13
    - To Boas, 1919 Dec. 7; 3p
  - Collier, John (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1923 Feb. 20; 1p
    - From Boas, 1923 Dev. 7; 2p
    - From Boas, 1935 May 13; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 June 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 June 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 June 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 June 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Dec.?; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 Feb. 1; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 May 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1923 Feb. 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1926 Jan. 19; 6p
    - To Boas, 1926 Jan. 27; 6p
    - Am. Ind. Defense Ass., Inc., 1926 May 8; 5p
    - enc.:, 1926 May 29; 4p
      - Re Ind. Med. Serv., 1926 Apr. 15; 1p
      - U.S. Bill S. 3611, Care of Wisconsin Indians
      - Goodrich, C.S. re: U.S. S. 3020 and S. 3611, 7p
      - Am. Ind. life dinner, 1926 June 3; 3p
      - Collier, J. re: Ind. policy of the U.S., 1926 June 1; 6p
    - To Boas, 1926 June 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Jan. 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Jan. 27; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 June 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 20; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Sep. 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 June 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Sep. 18; 1p
    - enc. Bronson, R.M. to Ryan, W.C., Jr., 1935 Sep. 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Sep. 18
    - To Boas, 1936 June 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Mar. 17; 1p
    - To Butler, N.M., 1936 Dec.?; 2p
  - Collin Fabrique d'Instruments de Chirurgie (Box 17)
    - To Boas, 1893 Feb. 10; 1p
  - Collins, B. (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1933 Sep. 14; 1p
  - Collins, Elizabeth M. (Box 17)
    - see FB open letter re Spain, replies, 1938 Jan.
  - Collins, H.B. Jr. (Box 17)
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 14; 1p
  - Collins, H.O. (Box 17)
    - To Boas, 1909 Nov. 19
  - Collins, Loyd A. (Box 17)
    - To Boas, 1909 Jan. 12
    - To Boas, 1909 Jan. 23
  - Collio Huaiquilaf, J.M. (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1925 Mar. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1925 Feb. 16; 1p
  - Colorado Scientific Soc. (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1909 Nov. 18
  - Colorado State Hist. & Nat. Hist. Soc. (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1933 Mar. 31; 1p
  - Colored Orphan Asylum (Box 17)
    See Pitman, Mason
  - Colucci, C. (Box 17)
    - From Prezzolini, G., 1935 Feb. 4
    - From Prezzolini, G., 1935 Feb. 7
    - From Prezzolini, G., 1935 Feb.?
  - Columbia Films (Box 17)
    See Gestures
    See Scenario Draft
  - Columbia Investment & Real Estate Co. (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1908 Dec. 1
    - From Boas, 1910 Mar. 10; 2p
    - From Boas, 1910 Mar. 14; 2p
    - From Boas, 1910 Mar. 17
    - To Boas, 1907 May 1
    - From Burney, William, 1912 July 26
  - Columbia Planograph Co. (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1909 Mar. 26
    - From Boas, 1909 Apr. 7
    - To Boas, 1909 Apr. 6
    - To Boas, 1909 Apr. 8
    - To Boas, 1909 May 29
  - COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY (Box 17)
    - General (Box 17)
      [Also N.B. categories to follow]
      - From Boas- Deutcher Verein, 1903 Nov. 5; 1p
      - From Boas- to Keppel, Sec'y, 1903 Nov. 6; 1p
      - From Boas to Bureau of Supplies, 1905 Mar. 11
      - From Boas to Com., Scholarships, 1905 Apr. 25
      - From Boas to Com., Scholarships, 1905 Apr. 29
      - From Boas to Com., Scholarships, 1905 May 11; 2p
      - From Boas to Fac., Philosophy, 1911 Apr. 6; 2p
      - From Boas to Fac., Pol. Sci., etc., 1913 Oct. 29; 11p
      - From Boas to Registrar, 1913 Nov. 14; 2p
      - From Boas to Barnard Anthrop., 1915 May; 3p
      - Columbia Anthrop.
      - (with Dewey & Woodworth), 1916 Feb. 2
      - From Boas to Registrar, 1920 Sep. 15; 1p
      - From Boas to Com. on Instruction, 1920 Oct. 12; 1p
      - From Boas to Fac. Club, 1920 Oct. 21; 1p
      - From Boas to Registrar, 1940 Jan. 11; 1p
      - From Boas to Teachers Coll., 1940 Jan. 22; 1p
      - To Boas- Plummer, J.F., 1897 Mar. 9; 1p
      - To Boas- Woodward, R.S., 1898 Jan. 20; 2p
      - To Boas- Woodward, R.S., 1898 May 18; 2p
      - To Boas- McWhood [?], L.B., 1898 Oct. 21; 1p
      - To Boas- Perry, Dean E.D., 1903 Feb. 10; 3p
      - To Boas- Supt., Bldgs., 1903 Apr. 28; 1p
      - To Boas- Keppel, F.P., Sec'y, 1903 Aug. 12; 1p
      - To Boas- Gilbert, W.M., 1903 Aug. 20; 1p
      - To Boas- Gilbert, W.M., 1903 Aug. 31; 1p
      - To Boas- Germanic Dept., 1903 Oct. 1
      - To Boas- Deutcher Verein, 1903 Oct. 31; 1p
      - To Boas- Keppel, F.P., 1903 Oct. 22; 1p
      - To Boas- Keppel, F.P., 1903 Oct. 29; 1p
      - To Boas- Perry, Dean E.D., 1903 Oct. 31; 1p
      - To Boas- Keppel, F.P., 1903 Nov. 4; 1p
      - To Boas- Keppel, F.P., 1903 Nov. 6; 1p
      - To Boas- Gilbert, W.M., 1903 Nov. 7; 1p
      - To Boas- Gilbert, W.M., 1903 Nov. 13; 1p
      - To Boas- Wadelton, H.C., 1903 Nov. 27; 1p
      - To Boas- Keppel, F.P., 1903 Dec. 9; 1p
      - To Boas- Chinese prince-ambass., 1904 Feb. 3; 1p
      - To Boas- Perry, Dean E.D., 1904 May 7; 1p
      - To Boas - University Coun., 1906 May 15
      - To Boas H.W. Tate, 1912 Oct. 3
      - To Boas Bldgs. & Grounds, 1912 Nov. 7
      - To Boas Univ. Council, 1913 Oct. 21
      - To Boas Statistics Course, 1913 Oct. 28; 2p
      - To Boas Barnard Coll., 1914 Mar.
      - To Boas Bldgs. & Grounds, 1916 June 30
      - To Boas Bldgs. & Grounds, 1917 May 31
      - To Boas see Hawkes, H.E., 1918 Dec.?; 6p
      - To Boas Multigraph Dept., 1919 Jan. 17; 1p
      - To Boas Printing Office, 1919 Feb. 27
      - To Boas Fac., Philosophy, 1919 Mar.; 1p
      - To Boas see FB to Woodworth, 1919 Mar. 12
      - To Boas Food Draft, Vienna, 1919 Mar. 25; 1p
      - To Boas Multigraph Dept., 1919 Nov. 22
      - To Boas Multigraph Dept., 1920 Sep. 30
      - To Boas Multigraph Dept., 1920 Oct. 23
      - To Boas Bill, 1930 Sep. 30
      - To Boas Bill, 1931 Mar. 31
      - To Boas Fac., Philosophy, 1931 May?; 3p
      - To Boas Pay order, 1934 May 31; 1p
      - To Boas Pay order, 1934 July 6
      - To Boas Pay order, 1934 Sep. 9
      - To Boas Pay order, 1935 May 31; 1p
      - To Boas Univ. sec'y, 1936 May 13; 1p
      - To Boas Coun., Research, Humanities, 1936 Oct. 14; 1p
      - To Boas Fac. Comm. Aid to Spanish, 1937 Dec. 9
        (see N.Y. Times)
      - To Boas Comm., Res., Native Sm. Languages, 1937 Dec.
      - To Boas Papers re teleg. to Prs. Roosevelt re Spain, 1938 Dec.
      - From Sargent, H.E., 1918 Apr. 24; 1p
      - From Cattell, J.M., 1918 Dec. 6; 1p
      - From Hunt, Geo., 1924 July 2; 1p
      - From Fatter, E., 1926 Mar. 25
      - From Ossman, Wm. G., 1930 Apr. 22; 1p
      - From Sargent, Rena P., 1930 May 1; 1p
      - From Hunt, Geo., 1930 June 27; 1p
      - From Hartman, J.P., 1930 Aug. 16
        - (see Fackenthal, F.D. to Hartman, J.P.), 1930 Aug. 22
      - From Iglehart, R. Lannert, 1933 Apr. 17; 1p
      - From Fackenthal, F.D., 1934 May 11
      - From Vaughn, W.C., 1936 Mar. 20
      - From Pourchet, M.J., 1936 Aug. 11
        - (see Meek, L.H.), 1936 Sep. 24
      - To Hermann, P., 1906 Feb. 7
      - To Haseltine, C.F., Jr., 1906 Dec. 4
      - To Benedict, R.F., 1932 July 1
    - Anthropology, Dept. of (Box 17)
      - Germanistic Soc., 1904 May 17; 1p
      - Budget, 1905 May 1
      - Budget, 1906 June 4
      - Expenditures, 1909 June 1
        - Boas allotment to Dept., 1912 May 10; 1p
        - Brit. Columbia Indians, 1913 Jan. 31
        - A.A. Goldenweiser courses, 1913 Feb. 25
        - Budget, 1914 Oct. 26
        - Appropriations 1913-17, 1917 Apr.; 3p
        - Brit. Columbia Indians, 1919 Jan.
        - Appropriation, 1919 Jan.
        - A.M. & Ph.D. courses, 1919 Jan.
        - Acc'ts, 1919 Feb.; 2p
        - Acc'ts, 1919 Mar.; 2p
        - Acc'ts, 1919 Apr.; 1p
        - Acc'ts, 1919 Apr.; 3p
        - Acc'ts, 1919 May; 2p
        - Acc'ts, 1919 July; 2p
        - Acc'ts, 1919 Aug.
        - Acc'ts, Brit. Columbia Ind., 1919 Oct.
        - Acc'ts, 1919 Nov.; 3p
        - Acc'ts, 1919 Dec.; 2p
        - Acc'ts, 1920 Jan.; 3p
        - Acc'ts, 1920 Feb.; 1p
        - Acc'ts, 1920 Mar.; 1p
        - Acc'ts, 1920 Apr.
        - Anthrop. 102 Exam, 1920 Sep.
        - Purchases & Supplies, 1920 Oct. 4
        - Allotment, 1920 Nov. 1
        - Acc't with Teit, J.A., 1921 May 31 to Dec 31; 1p
        - Budget, 1923
        - Budget, 1924
        - Budget enc. with Fackenthal, 1926 Apr. 5
        - Budget enc. with Fackenthal, 1927 Apr. 4
        - Budget enc. with Fackenthal, 1927 Sep. 17
        - Budget enc. with Fackenthal, 1929 Apr. 9
        - Budget enc. with Hayden, P., 1930 July 28
        - Candidates for M.A. degre, 1931 June
        - From Dewey, J., 1916 Feb. 2
        - From Woodworth, R.S., 1916 Feb. 2
        - From Pourchez, M.J., 1936 Apr. 1
        - From Pegram, G.B., 1936 June 15
    - Bursar (Box 17)
      - From Boas, 1909 Mar. 8
      - From Boas, 1917 Apr. 18
      - To Boas, 1917 Jan. 31
      - To Boas, 1917 Mar. 6
        - (open letter), 1938 July 20
      - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 19
      - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 12
      - To Boas, 1939 Mar. 20
    - Committee on Fellowships (Box 17)
      - 1936 Feb. 25, 1p
      - re Sapir, Edward D., 1906 Feb. 26
      - re Sapir, Edward D., 1923 Feb. 27; 1p
      - re Sapir, Edward D., 1923 Mar. 28; 1p
      - re Fortune, Reo, 1930 Feb. 27; 1p
      - re Laguna, F. de, 1930 Feb. 27; 1p
      - re Laguna, F. de, 1930 Mar. 18; 1p
      - re Laguna, F. de, 1931 Dec.?; 2p
      - re Dublin, Mary, 1933 Mar. 3; 1p
      - re Dublin, Mary, 1938 Mar. 11
    - Executive Officers of Departments (Box 17)
      - From Hayden, P.M., 1934 Apr. 16
    - Faculty Fellowship Committee (Box 17)
      - From Dunn, L.C., 1933 Aug. 11
      - Minutes, 1933 Oct. 31; 1p
      - Minutes, 1933 Nov.?; 2p
      - Report 1935-1941
        - (see Dunn, L.C. to Comm.), 1941 Jan. 7
        - (see Dunn, L.C. to Comm.), 1941 Jan. 10
    - Library (Box 17)
      - From Boas, 1920 Sep. 8; 1p
        - to Order Dept., 1920 Oct. 21; 1p
        - to Order Dept., 1920 Nov. 11; 1p
        - to Order Dept., 1931 Mar. 23; 1p
        - to Order Dept., 1931 Apr. 8; 1p
        - to Order Dept., 1931 Apr. 23; 1p
        - to Order Dept., 1931 May 7; 1p
        - to Order Dept., 1931 Sep. 29; 1p
      - From Boas, 1942 Nov. 9; 1p
      - To Boas from Canfield, J.H, 1903 May 18
      - List of Expenses, 1912 Dec. 4
      - To Boas from Canfield, J.H, 1914 Jan. 1
      - To Schurz, Carl L., 1920 Oct. 7; 1p
      - To Schurz, Carl L., bill, 1920 Nov. 17
    - Research Council of Social Sciences (Box 17)
      - Minutes, 1925 Feb. 2; 5p
      - From Boas:, 1927 Mar. 3; 6p
      - re Amer. Negro, 1927 Apr. 7; 1p
      - Klineberg, Otto report "Racial & Soc. Differences in Intelligence", 1929 Oct. 3; 1p
      - Minutes, organization meeting, 1925 Feb. 2; 5p
      - List of research projects, 1928 Dec. 31(?); 3p
      - Approved research projects, 3p
      - Minutes, 1929 Oct.; 1p
      - Minutes extract, 1930 Oct. 13; 2p
      - From Ross, F.A., 1931 Apr. 28
        - enc. with MacIver, R.M., 1931 Apr. 30
      - Agenda, 1934 May 15; 1p
        - enc. with Hayden, P.M., 1934 May 15
      - Meeting notice, 1936 Oct. 13; 1p
        enc. Burnside, C.H. Hayes, C.J.H. Carpenter, C.R. McFarland, R.A.
      - To McFarland, Ross, 1938 Mar. 21; 1p
      - From Hayden, P.M., 1934 May 15
    - Trustees (Box 17)
      - 1905 Apr. 5, 1p
      - Abstract of minutes, 1930 Nov. 3; 4p
      - Abstract of minutes, 1931 Jan. 5; 5p
      - Abstract of minutes, 1931 Feb. 2; 4p
      - Abstract of minutes, 1931 Mar. 2; 4p
      - Abstract of minutes, 1931 Nov. 2; 3p
      - Abstract of minutes, 1931 May 4; 7p
      - Abstract of minutes, 1932 Oct. 3; 1p
      - Abstract of minutes, 1932 Dec. 5; 1p
      - Abstract of minutes, 1933 Jan. 9; 1p
      - Abstract of minutes, 1934 Nov. 5; 1p
      - Abstract of minutes, 1942 Apr. 6; 1p
      - From Frachtenberg, L.J., 1917 June 11
      - From Sargent, H.E., 1917 Nov. 19
      - From Cattell, J.M., 1918 Mar. 26; 3p
      - From Sargent, H.E., 1919 Sep. 1
      - From Cattell, J.M., 1921 Sep. 21; 5p
      - From Sargent, H.E., 1927 Oct. 11
      - From Sargent, H.E., 1929 Aug. 8
    - Univ. Federation for Democ. & Intellec. Freedom (Box 17)
      [See also Amer. Committee for Democ. & Intellec. Freedom]
      - Papers, 1938 Dec.
      - Constitution, 1939 Dec.; 3p
      - Pamphlets about self, 1939 Dec.; 4p
      - To U.S. Congress. House, 1939 Dec.; 1p
      - Papers, 1939 Dec.; 4p
      - Tentative program 1939-40, 1939 Dec.; 5p
      - History & Constitution, 1940 Dec.; 4p
      - Open letter, 1940 Dec.; 1p
  - C.U. Press (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1930 Apr. 24; 1p
      See Carpenter, Wm. H.
  - Columbian Museum, Chicago (Box 17)
    - Exhibit awards, 1894 Apr. 30; 3p
  - Columbian Univ., Washington (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 21; 1p
  - Comacho, Pedro (Box 17)
    - To Boas, 1912 Feb.?
    - To Boas, 1912 Mar. 7
  - Comas, Juan (Box 17)
    - To Amer. Comm. for Democ. & Intellec. Freedom, 1941 Dec.; 1p
  - Comer, George M. (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1906 May 12
    - From Boas, 1906 June 15
    - From Boas, 1906 Dec. 1
    - From Boas, 1906 Dec. 5
    - From Boas, 1907 May 18; 2p
    - From Boas, 1907 May 22
    - From Boas, 1907 June 1
    - From Boas, 1910 May 27
    - From Boas, 1910 May 31; 2p
    - From Boas, 1912 Nov. 1
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 2
    - From Boas, 1912 Jan. 20, 1913 Jan. 27
    - From Boas, 1913 Oct. 7
    - From Boas, 1913 Nov. 1
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 2
    - From Boas, 1930 Apr. 17
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 15
    - To Boas, 1906 May 23
      Location
      Item not found in folder 2009.
    - To Boas, 1906 Dec. 8
    - To Boas, 1907 May 20
    - To Boas, 1907 May 26
    - To Boas, 1908 July 26
    - To Boas, 1908 June 6, 1910 May 30
    - To Boas, 1912 Oct. 29
    - To Boas, 1912 Nov. 4
    - To Boas, 1913 Jan. 18
    - To Boas, 1913 Jan. 21, 29
    - To Boas, 1913 June 26
    - To Boas, 1913 Oct. 10; 2p
    - To Boas, 1913 Oct. 24
    - To Boas, 1913 Nov. 4
    - To Boas, 1914 Jan. 26
    - To Boas, 1916 Nov. 22
    - To Boas, 1917 Oct. 22
    - To Boas, 1930 Apr. 16
    - To Miss Andrews, 1906 June 23; 5p
  - Comer, J.L. (Mrs. G.M.) (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 5
    - To Boas, 1917 Jan. 28
  - Comer Collection (Box 17)
    Inuit artifacts
    - 1912 Nov., 12p
  - Comez, F.V. (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1917 Jan. 31; 2p
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 24
  - Comité d'Initiative pour l'Action internationale contre les Doctrines racist (Box 17)
    - see Mauco, G., 1937 Aug. 12
  - Comité international permanent de linguistes (Box 17)
    - Ordre du jour, 1929 June 14-15
    - see Schrijnen, J., 1929 June 30
    - misc. resolutions, etc., 1929 Dec. 31
  - Comité Nobel du Parliament norwégien (Box 17)
    - 1905 Apr. 10, 2p
    - from Dewey, John, 1936 Jan.
  - Commerzbibliothek Hamburg (Box 17)
    see Rosenbaum
  - Committee [?] (Box 17)
    - enc. Shapiro, H.L., 1938 Oct. 25; 5p
    - Burks, B.S.
    - Theis, S.V.S. to Burks, B.S., 1937 July 28
  - Committee -- [on anthropology?] (Box 17)
    - enc. Kallmann, Franz paper, 1938 Oct. 17
  - Committee, Advisory, on Research on Indian Languages (Box 17)
    - see F.B. open letter, 1927 June 21
    - see F.B. open letter, 1927 June 23
  - Committee for Assistance of Lesser Nationalities of U.S.S.R. of Leniingrad (Box 17)
    - From Duggan, S.P. with Duggan, S.P., 1928 Nov. 19
  - Committee for Austrian Relief (Box 17)
    - Minutes, 1938 Mar. 31; 8p
  - Committee for Concerted Peace Efforts Comm. to study revision of neutrality legislation (Box 17)
    - Report, 1939 Jan. 26; 4p
  - Committee for Cultural Freedom (Box 17)
    - Report No. 2, 1940 Apr. 31
  - Committee for Defense of Public Education (Box 17)
    - Statement, 1941 Aug. 2
      - enc. FB to Amer. Fed. of Teachers, 1941 July 31
  - Committee in Aid of Refugee Scholars from Spain (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1939 May 22; 1p
  - Committee of Catholics to Fight Anti-Semitism (Box 17)
    - members - enc. with Chapman, E., 1939 May 26
  - Committee of Forty-Eight (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1919 Sep. 5; 5p
    - From Boas, 1919 Sep. 8
  - Committee on American Indian Languages (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1938 Mar 28
  - Committee on American Indian Linguistics (Box 17)
    - From Boas to Bloomfield, L. Kroeber, A.L. Swadesh, M., 1939 Dec. 18
  - Committee on Research in Native American Languages (Box 17)
    - enc. with letter from Leland, W.G. to F.B., 1938 Jan. 25; 3p
  - Committee on [Research on] Amer. Native Languages (Box 17)
    - Statement 1/1-10/1/39, 1939 Oct. 1
    - Statement 1/1-12/31/39, 1939 Dec. 31
    - From Boas, 1940 Jan. 11
    - From Boas, 1940 Jan. 11
      - to Bloomfield, Kroeber & Swadesh, 1940 Jan. 16; 2p
      - to Bloomfield, Kroeber & Swadesh, 1940 Jan. 19
    - From Boas, 1940 Feb. 9
    - financial statement, 1940 Feb. 28
    - financial statement 3/1-6/1, 1940 June
      - to Bloomfield, Hoijer, Kroeber & Swadesh, 1940 Apr. 29
  - Committee on Intellectual Freedom (Box 17)
    - see FB to Klapper, P., 1938 Apr. 7
  - Committee on Studies in Determination of Population Qualities by Genetic & Environmental Factors (Box 17)
    - See Burks, B.L. folder for enclosure on project on foster children, 1939 Oct. 3
  - Committee on the Study of the American Negro (Box 17)
    - Proposals, 1927 Feb.?; 5p
    - Proposals d enc. with FB to Columbia U. Research Coun. of Soc. Sciences, 1927 Apr. 7
    - see Terry, R.J., 1929 Mar. 22
  - Committee to Defend America by Keeping Out of War (Box 17)
    - 1940 July 27
  - Community Church of N.Y. (Box 17)
    - From Boas to Bd. of Trustees, 1938 Nov. 3
  - Compania Mexicana de Express, S.A. (Box 17)
    - Receipt, 1911 Dec. 30
  - Compton, Arthur H. (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1933 May 23
      - See FB to Wheeler, W.M., 1933 May 23
    - To Boas, 1939 Sep. 16
    - To Boas, 1940 June 6
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec. 5
    - To Boas, 1941 Nov. 12
  - Compton, K.T. (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1933 May 23
      - See FB to Wheeler, W.M., 1933 May 23
    - From Boas, 1933 June 1
    - To Boas, 1933 May 31
    - To Boas, 1941 Nov. 11
    - To Bush, V., 1933 May 31
  - Comstock, A. (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1931 June 6
    - To Boas, 1931 June 16
  - Conal, Bernard (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1939 Jan. 8
    - From Boas, 1940 Apr. 25
    - To Boas, 1939 June 21; 3p
    - To Boas, 1939 July 15
    - To Boas, 1939 July 17
    - To Boas, 1939 July 20
    - To Boas, 1939 July 29; 2p
    - To Boas, 1939 Aug. 3; 2p
    - enc. Hrdlieka-Neilson, 1939 Dec. 20 and Dec. 26
    - To Boas, 1940 Oct. 11
    - enc. FB notes, Nat'l Fed. for Constitu. Liberties & NY Conf. for Inalienable Rights, 1941 Feb. 20
  - Conant, J.B. (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1938 Oct. 27
    - To Boas, 1938 Oct. 31
  - Conant, L. (Box 17)
    - To Boas, 1898 Oct. 15
  - Conference on Democracy & Universal Peace (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1917 May 28
  - Conference on Pan-American Democracy (Box 17)
    - Continuations Com. Minutes, 1938 Dec. 19; 2p
    - see McConnell, D., 1938 Dec. 1
      - Soule, Geo., 1938 Dec. 11
    - Paper, 1938 Dec. 31; 2p
    - see Edel, B. notes, enc., 1938 Dec. 31
  - Conference on Research in the American Languages (Box 17)
    - 1927 Apr. 2, 3p
  - Conference on Science, Philosophy, and Religion in Their Relation to the Democratic Way of Life (Box 17)
    - List of founders, 1940 May 21
    - see Finkelstein, Louis, 1940 May 28
  - Congedo, Father (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1936 Mar. 31; 2p
  - Conger, E.E. (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1930 Dec. 19
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 12
    - From Boas, 1931 Feb. 16
    - To Boas, 1930 Dec. 18
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 13
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 12
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 26
  - Congres International d'Histoire des Religions (Box 17)
    - Announcement, 1923 Jan.; 3p
  - Congres International de la Population (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1937 June 17; 1p
    - Invitation and paper, 1937 July 29-Aug. 1; 6p
    - Bulletin, 1937 Dec. 31; 1p
      see Mauco, G.
  - Congress of Americanists (Box 17)
    - Constitution and By-laws, 1900 n.d.; 2p
    - Resolution on death of A.S. Gatschet, 1909 Dec. 31; 1p
    - Lima Congress program, 1939 June; 4p
  - Conklin, Edwin Grant (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 20
    - From Boas, 1917 Oct. 18
    - From Boas, 1917 Oct. 23
    - From Boas, 1917 Oct. 29
    - From Boas, 1917 Nov. 8; 5p
    - From Boas, 1919 Mar. 18; 5p
    - From Boas, 1919 Apr. 9; 2p
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 26; 1p
    - From Boas, 1923 Feb. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1929 Jan. 24; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Dec. 27; 2p
    - From Boas, 1935 May 9; 2p
    - From Boas, 1938 June 14; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 June 22; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 June 23; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Sep. 19; 1p
    - From Boas, 1941 Oct. 23; 2p
    - From Boas, 1941 Nov. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1941 Dec. 19; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 Nov. 4; 2p
    - To Boas, 1917 Oct. 22
    - To Boas, 1917 Nov. 1
    - To Boas, 1917 Nov. 9
    - To Boas, 1919 Mar. 20; 1p
    - To Boas, 1923 Feb. 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Dec. 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 May 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 June 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Mar. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Oct. 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Nov. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Dec. 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Nov. 12; 1p
    - see Amer. Philosoph. Soc., 1941 Dec. 22
    - From Boas, E.P., 1943 Mar. 3
      - Sherwin, P., 1920 May 22; 1p
      - Stefansson, V., 1942 Oct. 29
  - Conley, W.G. (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1932 pr. 6; 1p
  - Conreid, Heinrich (Box 17)
    - From Boas, 1905 Dec. 19; 1p
    - From Boas, 1905 Jan. 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1906 Feb. 19; 1p
    - From Boas, 1906 Feb. 20; 1p
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 27; 1p